Brian David Tabuada

Senior Software Engineer

I am a quick-learning Software Engineer with over four years of experience and strong time and task management skills. I excel in fastpaced environments and am adaptable to changing requirements. My experience and adaptability make me a valuable asset to any team.

david.brian.dev@gmail.com



+639669003600



Imus, Cavite, Philippines



davidbrian.github.io

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer DBOS

04/2021 - 04/2022

Tasks:

- Developing new features and functionality for the app.
- Troubleshooting and fixing bugs and other issues with the app.
- Maintaining and updating the app to ensure it remains stable and secure.
- Collaborating with other team members to identify and implement improvements to the app.

Tech Stack: ReactJS, Material- UI, ExpressJS, PostgreSQL, Bitbucket, and Amazon RDS.

Software Engineer

YNS Philippines Inc.

09/2019 - 03/2021

Tech Stack:

- I contributed to the development of the microservice by working on its business logic, designing and implementing API endpoints, developing a custom rules algorithm, and implementing UI/UX designs.
- · Engineering a messaging bot.
- Creating a WordPress plugin.
- Designing and developing a web-based tool for storing and comparing test evidences.
- Developing a hybrid mobile app.

Tech Stack: API, CSS, Docker, Express Js, jQuery, jQuery UI, JS, Node Js, Onsen UI, Postman, SQL, Swagger, Vue Js, WordPress (hooks and filters), AngularJs, Bootstrap, Cakephp3, Deep links with OG meta, Line messaging API, Messenger Platform, ThickBox, Webhooks, and Auto in-app update, Monaca

Web Developer

Intern @ TSPG IT SOLUTIONS

01/2019 - 04/2019

Achievements/Tasks

- · Developing a web-based application for an online book of accounts and invoicing.
- Designing and developing a website for the online House & Condo showcase portfolio.

Tech Stack: SymfonyPHP, Bootstrap, Sass, Webpack, Adobe XD and jQuery.

Web Developer

Freelance

06/2017 - 12/2018

Achievements/Tasks

- · Designing and developing a statistics monitoring system with e-commerce capabilities for a pineapple farm.
- Developing an attendance management system for a dance studio.
- Designing and developing mobile responsive themes for web applications.

Tech Stack: PHP, Bootstrap, jQuery, RFID development kit, Chart.js, Facebook Messenger bot, and SOL.

SKILLS

ReactJS, AngularJS, VueJs, & Jquery.

CSS, HTML, JS.

Material UI, Tailwind CSS, & Bootstrap.

Mysql, Postgress, SQLite, Redis, MongoDB & Firebase

Docker, Git, scripting/automation & Linux commands.

Rest API, RPC API, Webhooks, sync/async, & websockets.

NodeJS & PHP. (ExpressJS, Socket.IO, Laravel, CakePHP, Symfony, etc)

EDUCATION

BS in Information Technology Far Eastern University - Cavite 06/2019

CERTIFICATES

NATIONAL CERTIFICATE III in VISUAL **GRAPHIC DESIGN**

NATIONAL CERTIFICATE II in COMPUTER SYSTEMS SERVICING

NATIONAL CERTIFICATE III in 2D ANIMATION

INTERESTS

Automation

Machine learning

Web accessibility

Internet of things